A Guide to the Virginia Commission on State Governmental Management Records, 1973-1978
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Commission on State Governmental Management Records, 1973-1978
The Library of Virginia
29887
37.35 cu. ft. (83 boxes)
Virginia. Commission on State Governmental Management.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred 27 March 1978 from the Commission on State Governmental Management, 6 N. 6th Street, Richmond, VA 23219. [Acc. 29887].
Transferred 18 September 1978 from the Commission on State Governmental Management, 6 N. 6th Street, Richmond, VA 23219 and interfiled. [Acc. 30074].
Biographical Information
Virginia's population growth and urbanization during the 1960s increased demand for state services and led to the creation of an assortment of new state agencies. The rapid growth of state government fueled concerns that state services were not provided in the most efficient and economical manner. On February 18, 1970, Governor Linwood Holton created the Governor's Management Study, Inc., a non-profit, privately funded corporation, empowered to improve and reduce the cost of providing governmental services to the state's citizens and reduce the number of departments reporting directly to the Governor. The Study, composed of private citizens and business leaders, submitted its final report in November 1970. Its main recommendation was the creation of a cabinet system to streamline the executive branch and reduce the demands on the Governor's time. The General Assembly concurred and created six cabinet secretaries in 1972. However, the act did not clearly define the duties and powers of the secretaries. This problem, along with the belief that the Governor's Management Study did not have sufficient time to conduct a comprehensive study of state government, led the legislature to create its own commission.
The Commission on State Governmental Management was created by an act of the General Assembly approved on March 20, 1973. The commission initially was composed of fifteen members: seven appointed by the speaker from the membership of the House of Delegates, four appointed by the Senate Privileges and Elections Committee from the Senate's membership, and four appointed by the governor from the state at large. In 1976 the commission's number was increased to sixteen, and the House Committee on General Laws appointed the new member. Patrick M. McSweeney served as Executive Director and Kenneth Golden served as Deputy Director of the Commission. The commission was also known as the Hopkins Commission after its chairman, Senator William B. Hopkins.
The goal of the commission was to recommend changes in the organization of state government that would result in a reduction in the number of agencies, less duplication of effort, clearer lines of authority, and undivided responsibilities for particular functions of government. The act creating the commission specified certain areas for study that were later increased in number and stipulated that an interim report be presented to the governor and the General Assembly by October 1, 1973, and a final report be presented by October 1, 1974. These deadlines were extended three times until a final report was required by October 1, 1977, and it was ordered that "all work of the commission be terminated no later than March 31, 1978."
To assist the commission in its work a staff of consultants and researchers was assembled. The commission published interim reports and studies of particular areas of state government. Some but not all of the commission's recommendations were adopted and enacted into law. Two major recommendations adopted were the revision and strengthening of the secretarial system and the creation of the Department of Planning and Budget.
Scope and Content
Records, 1973-1978, containing the working papers and records of the Virginia Commission on State Governmental Management. Senator William B. Hopkins was chairman of the Commission which was often called the Hopkins Commission. Included are budget reports, correspondence, reports, memoranda, speeches, minutes, vouchers, and research notes. Also included are questionnaires submitted by departments within state agencies; and reports and studies of other states that had similar government reorganization groups.
Contents List
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 February (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 April (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 July (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 August (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 September (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 October (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 November (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1974 December (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 January (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 February (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 March (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, "Information Papers," 1975 March-September (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 April (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 June (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 July (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 August (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 September (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 October (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 November (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1975 December (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 January (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 February (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 March (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 April (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 May (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 June (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 July (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 August (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 September (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 October (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 November (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1976 December (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1977 January (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1977 February (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1977 March (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Outgoing correspondence, Patrick McSweeney, 1977 April (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 February (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 March (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 April (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 May (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 June (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 July (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 August (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 September (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 October (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1974 December (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1975 January (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1975 February (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1975 April-December (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1977 January-April (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1977 May (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1977 June (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1977 July (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1977 August-September (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1977 October-December (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Outgoing correspondence, Kenneth Golden, 1978 January-March (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Outgoing correspondence, General, 1978 January-March (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Outgoing correspondence, William D. Van Stavoren, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Outgoing correspondence, William D. Van Stavoren, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Outgoing correspondence, William D. Van Stavoren, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Outgoing correspondence, Dorothy Boland (Research assistant), 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Outgoing correspondence, Paul R. Gilding (Commonwealth intern), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Outgoing correspondence, Janipher Greene (Research assistant), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Outgoing correspondence, Margaret I. Lane (Staff assistant), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Outgoing correspondence, Susie NeSmith (Secretary), 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Outgoing correspondence, Melanie L. Rhoades (Research assistant), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Outgoing correspondence, Charles Tulloh, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Outgoing correspondence, General, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Outgoing correspondence, General, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Incoming correspondence, General, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Incoming correspondence, General, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Incoming correspondence, Legislators, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Attorney General, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, ADP, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Briefing paper, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Budget, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Budget, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Budget, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Capital Outlay Analysis, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Commissions and Boards, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, Commonwealth Intern, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Summer Interns, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Consultant contract, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Education, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, Education, Secretary of, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Education, Superintendent of, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Employment, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Environmental reorganization, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, Executive Management Services, Inc., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Federal Regional Council, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, Governor, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, Highway Safety Project Grant, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, Information, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Intergovernmental Affairs, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, First Interim Report, 1974 January (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Second Interim Report, 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Third Interim Report, 1974 December (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Lieutenant Governor, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Meeting, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Monthly Status Reports, 1975 November (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Organization, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Personnel Study, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
- Correspondence, Product Commissioner, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Public Authorities, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Questionnaire, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, Requests for Assistance, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Requests for Information or Publications, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Resource Personnel and Support, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Secretary, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, Subcommittee Reports, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Transportation and Public Safety Issues, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, Work Program, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Agendas, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Background material, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Commission meetings, Meeting with Senator Hopkins, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Commission meetings, 1974 May (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Commission meetings, 1974 June (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Commission meetings, 1974 September (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Commission meetings, 1974 November (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Commission meetings, 1974 December (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Commission meetings, 1975 April (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Commission meetings, 1975 May (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Commission meetings, 1975 June (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Commission meetings, 1975 July (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Commission meetings, 1975 August (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Commission meetings, 1975 September (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Commission meetings, 1975 October (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Commission meetings, 1975 November (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Commission meetings, 1976 April (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Commission meetings, 1976 May (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Commission meetings, 1976 June (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Commission meetings, 1976 August (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Commission meetings, 1976 November (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Commission meetings, 1976 December (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Commission meetings, 1977 April (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
- Commission meetings, 1977 May (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
- Commission meetings, 1977 August (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Commission meetings, 1977 September (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Commission meetings, 1977 November (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Commission meetings, 1977 December (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Acts of Assembly, Chapter 432, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Staff projects, 1974 April (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Outline of proposal to the National Science Foundation, 1974 May (Box 8, Folder 3)
- State's Management Processes, 1974 June (Box 8, Folder 4)
- The need to preserve the Executive budget process, 1974 July (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Employment in the Executive branch, 1974 August (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Supplemental staff material: Definitions, 1974 August (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Working assumptions concerning organization, 1974 September (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Outline of Individual Area and Group Reports on State Program Undertakings and Organization, 1974 September (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Overview of Commission Activities, 1974 September (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Meetings scheduled, 1974 October (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Transportation study, 1974 October (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Role of state government in human affairs, 1974 October (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Report on the organizational structure and operation of selected state departments of transportation, 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Programs and activities of Virginia State Government, 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Government operations Subcommittee meeting, 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Recommendations on the Secretaries, 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Subcommittee on budget and management systems report on the state's budget roles, 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Team of eight analysts report on governmental operations, 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Policy questions on the organizational structure of Virginia state government, 1974 December (Box 8, Folder 20)
- The provision of transportation facilities and services in Virginia: Existing organizational structure and implications for the future, 1974 December (Box 8, Folder 21)
- A study of state government expenditures (1959-1973), 1974 December (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Collegial bodies, 1974 December (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Subcommittee on government operations, Report on major purpose areas of state government, Areas of secretarial responsibility, 1974 December (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Time for Stock-Taking, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Alternatives for reorganization of state government: Natural Resources, Agriculture, Commerce and Labor, 1975 January (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Report of subcommittee on office of Lieutenant Governor, 1975 January (Box 8, Folder 27)
- State agency background papers, Part Two: Human Affairs, 1975 February (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Proposals for reorganization of state government: Natural Resources, 1975 February (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Reorganization of Natural Resources activities, 1975 February (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Bills that failed to pass the General Assembly, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Staff report on pending legislation, 1975 February (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Proposals for reorganization of state government: Human Resources, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 6)
- General outline for a state personnel study, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Functions of collegial bodies, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 8)
- The role of the Chief Executive in state government, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Background on Dickinson County, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Proposed Human Resources reorganization, 1975 March (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Report on the Virginia highway maintenance and construction fund, 1975 April (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Collegial bodies, 1975 April (Box 9, Folder 13)
- State agency background papers, Part Three: Agriculture, Commerce and Labor, 1975 April (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Subcommittee on government operations, 1975 April (Box 9, Folder 15)
- The impact of federal requirements on the organization of the state's human affairs activities, 1975 May (Box 9, Folder 16)
- How should the activities in the Administration and Finance Area be organized?, 1975 May (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Organizing executive management functions, 1975 May (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Organization of the activities in the Administration and Finance Area, 1975 May (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Recommendations on the responsibilities and administration of state agencies in the Commonwealth in the Human Affairs and Natural Resources areas, 1975 June (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Subcommittee on government operations report on the organization of the Commonwealth's Natural Resources and Human Resources Activities, 1975 June (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Proposal for reorganization of state government: Administration and Finance, 1975 June (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Proposal for reorganization of state government: Agriculture, Commerce and Labor, 1975 June (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Secretaries roles, 1975 June (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Organization of the Office of Administration and Finance, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 1)
- State planning and Community Affairs, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Supplement to staff paper on Transportation, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Proposal for reorganization of state government, Part Four: Transportation, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 4)
- State Agency background papers, Part Four: Transportation, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Outline for presentation on the role of the Secretaries, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Comparison of state full-time employment, 1975 June (Box 10, Folder 7)
- State Agency background papers, Part Five: Education, 1975 July (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Proposals for reorganization of State Government: Education, 1975 July (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Transportation organization and management, 1975 July (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Recommendations regarding the Office of Attorney General, 1975 August (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Proposals for reorganization of State Government, Part Six: Public Safety, 1975 August (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Overview of future state transportation expenditures and revenues, 1975 August (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Commission meeting, 1975 August (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Proposals for reorganization of State Government: Public Safety, 1975 September (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Mass transportation in Northern Virginia, 1975 September (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Division of personnel comments, 1975 September (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Reorganization of Public Safety activities, 1975 September (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Executive functions of the State Corporation Commission of Virginia, 1975 October (Box 10, Folder 19)
- State Corporation Commission, 1975 October (Box 10, Folder 20)
- A report for public discussion: Management of Virginia state government, 1975 November (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Problems in State government, 1975 November (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Draft statues, 1975 December (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Background Report No. 4: Reorganization activities in other states, 1975 December (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Planning and Budget system, 1975 December (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Memorandum concerning final recommendations and alternative implementation approaches, 1975 December (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Review of Commission's activities, 1976 March (Box 11, Folder 4)
- A description of the effort to redefine and improve the management structure and processes in Virginia State Government, 1976 April (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Background paper on the reorganization of state transportation activities and services, 1976 April (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Commission staff work assignments, 1976 April (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Virginia's agricultural product commissions, 1976 April (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Summary of state agency comments on the proposed reorganization in Human Resources, 1976 May (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Suggested speech, 1976 May (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Public relations, 1976 June (Box 11, Folder 11)
- State Corporation Commission, 1976 July (Box 11, Folder 12)
- The regulation of professions and occupations in Virginia, 1976 July (Box 11, Folder 13)
- The Work of the Commission on State Governmental Management, 1976 July (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Employment in selected State Departments of Transportation, 1976 July (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Priorities for General Assembly, 1976 August (Box 11, Folder 16)
- The Work of the Commission on State Governmental Management, 1976 August (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Report on insurance, 1976 August (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Banking and State Corporation Commission powers, 1976 August (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Highlights of the Commission, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Improving State Governmental Management: A summary of priority recommendations, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Presentation to the Land Use Advisory Committee, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Meeting of the Committee on Natural Resources, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Insurance revisions, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Presentation to the American Institute of Planners, Virginia Chapter, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Public Utilities: Motor Carriers, 1976 September (Box 11, Folder 26)
- W.L. Lemmon's speech, 1976 October (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Reorganization proposals: Creating a Department of Enforcement and Investigation, 1976 December (Box 11, Folder 28)
- State purchasing function, 1976 December (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Commission estimate of revenue and expenditures, 1976 December (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Transportation, 1976 December (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Review of the Commission's eighteen priority recommendations, 1976 December (Box 11, Folder 32)
- ,Bills concerning the State Corporation Commission 1977 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Report on Sunset Laws, 1977 January (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Patrick McSweeney remarks, 1977 January (Box 12, Folder 2)